Jessica Filippelli 40046560
CART 263 - Project 3 Response

The Harry Potter Match Game

For the final project I wanted to do something meaningful to me. I've had a love for Harry Potter since I was a kid, there's nothing better than doing a project on something that brings a person happiness. I created a match game to test user's knowledge on Harry Potter characters. This game can be for those who are Harry Potter fans and want to see if they can get all the matches right or it can be for those who want to mess around with the game and see what happens.

The reason behind the notion of a match game was that I wanted to use something that I've never used before and when I was doing research on what JQUERY elements to use the draggable element from JQUERY UI caught my eye. The draggable element is one of the main elements that helps the game work. 

How the game works is that a user matches images of the Harry Potter characters with information on the character that is supposed to act as a hint to guess correctly. The information is displayed with the help of a JSON file, the images are the draggable elements. A user drops the image into the JQUERY UI element called droppable. A way to keep the game interesting is that I added audio when a user gets the question right. When the user gets the question wrong, Responsive Voice will speak the word “Wrong”. When A user drags an image and it is wrong, that image will slide back to where it originally was. This gives the project a nice little effect and is a bit less static. There is also the option when a user does not know the answer, they have the option to skip the person’s information and will give you a new one. All they have to do is say skip, and this is done with anayan. To keep track of how many matches a user has gotten right the score will go up by one each time. When the user has guessed all the right matches that means the game is over and a popup screen will open saying “you won” and with a button to play again? 

There is a homepage with the game caption and instructions. I made the game into two pages because when I had the captions, the instructions and the game all on one page I thought it all looked squished and I did not like how it looked. I thought there was too much going on. With two pages it breaks things up and looks nicer. To give it a Harry Potter design, I made the main page have a background with the four Harry Potter house colors. 

The images are from the Harry Potter Wiki (https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/Main_Page) and from google images. 
The Sound is from the YouTube creative studio. 
